Gabriel Diegel

Email: gabriel.diegel@icloud.com Github: https://github.com/gdiegel

Professional Summary

Creative Software Engineer with 15 years of demonstrated experience in Software Engineering, Solutions Architecture, and Technology Leadership. Deep expertise in Distributed Systems, Microservices, Event-Driven Architecture, and Continuous Delivery. Highly motivated self-starter with a winning mindset and a bias for action.

Currently

Staff Software Engineer at Nearsure in Lima, Peru

Programming languages

Java, Go, Kotlin, Python

Technologies

Spring Boot, WebFlux, Quarkus, Echo, Docker, Kubernetes, Git, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Pub/Sub, Maven, Gradle, Google Cloud Platform, AWS, Terraform, Datadog

Experience

2024-current

Staff Software Engineer at Nearsure in Lima, Peru

• Lead development of next-generation schedule import solution

2023-2024

Senior Software Engineer at Nearsure in Lima, Peru

- Lead architectural modernization efforts with new microservice-based backend
- \bullet Designed and implemented event-driven state synchronization system
- Solved performance issues, making legacy endpoints up to 90% faster

2019-2022

Senior Software Engineer at Tekton in Lima, Peru

- Developed microservice-based backend for US fintech
- Implemented event-driven architecture

2018-2019

Senior Software Development Engineer in Test at 161 Internet SE in Karlsruhe, Germany

- Developed modular test strategy, tooling, and reporting for web-based frontend tests
- Developed and supported strategy and framework for integrating functional acceptance tests into company-wide continuous delivery framework
- Planned, executed and analyzed performance tests for next-generation backend store architecture and Single-Sign-On solution, implemented metrics and data gathering in InfluxDB, analyzed and visualized data in Grafana
- Supervised theses of graduate students
- Lead test automation guild

2013-2018

Software Development Engineer in Test at 1&1 Internet SE in Karlsruhe, Germany

- Developed acceptance test suites in Java for a broad range of backend services using protocols like HTTP,
 SMTP, IMAP, and POP3
- Developed declarative framework in Java for HTTP-based API tests
- Developed RESTful web service with Spring Boot for collecting metrics of deployed software artifacts

2010-2012

Analyst at Atos Worldline GmbH in Frankfurt, Germany

- Analyzed data reports drawn from large-scale customer data and transaction database
- Developed a CLI tool in Python for data management, extracting data from mainframe database, filtering, and automatically loading into Oracle databases

2009-2010

2009

Software Engineer at Fraunhofer Institute for Physical Measurement Techniques IPM in Freiburg, Germany

- Developed software for an automated particle detection system
- Integrated a fast hardware-based data acquisition system

Education

B.Sc. in Psychology at Universität Hagen, Germany

Dipl.-Ing. (FH) in Electrical Engineering at Hochschule Karlsruhe, Germany

Thesis: "Development of an automated image analysis software for a fluorescence-based data acquisition system for the detection of airborne microorganisms"

Projects

2016 retryJ: A re

retryJ: A retry library for Java

Languages

German: Native English: Fluent Spanish: Fluent Italian: Learning

Articles

"Take your testing DSL to the next level with custom assertions"
"JUnit5—Feeble screams from forests well known"
"Using neo-problem with a pure Spring Boot service"
"Writing a custom test engine with Kotlin"

2019 "Automated acceptance testing"

2019 "Running acceptance tests on GitlabCI"